Peter Abeln

6619 Irving Ave S·Minneapolis, MN 55423 petron@gmail.com 612 206-2668

Summary

Experienced Full Stack application developer looking for a challenging and rewarding opportunities using established Front End frameworks. I'm comfortable working on a team and as a mentor as well as with database administrators, project or product managers and designers in the software development cycle.

Career Skills

- 18 years of web development/interface design
- 13 years of web development and database application
- 13 years of web server administration with IIS & Apache

Primary Skills

- Responsive/adaptive website and application development
- UX/UI design and QA analysis
- API development SOAP and RESTful
- Third party API integration web security and authentication
- Plan, research, organize and execute web design/development projects
- Web server management and configuration
- Database development and maintenance
- Team development and collaboration on small to large projects/builds

Languages/Markup/Frameworks

PHP/Laravel jQuery
HTML5 Gulp/Webpack
JavaScript/TypeScript NPM/Node.JS
CSS3/LESS/SCSS Bootstrap 3.x
APIs - SOAP, REST & RESTful Firebase

Tools

LAMP & WAMP stacks

Sublime Text/Brackets/VS Code

Adobe CC suite

GIT/SVN

Microsoft SQL Server - Mgmt Studio

Apache/IIS

MAMP Pro

Chrome Dev Tools

MySQL - Workbench

Windows/MacOS

Education Highlights

- [Starts Jan 15, 2019] University of Minnesota Coding Boot Camp Full Stack Flex Program
- Ecommerce Web Design and Development Program, Associate's Degree, Minnesota School of Business, Minneapolis, MN
- BS in Business Management, University of Phoenix Online Program

Recent Projects

• VMware.com/timeline

Worked with our San Francisco office and their designer to create this JavaScript-heavy interactive animated page

Geosys.com

Worked on a team using the AGILE method and created a highly customized WordPress/PHP website

• AmericanBrainFoundation.org

An e-commerce donation with many client requested modifications using PHP

• TaxpayerRightsConference.com

Worked closely with our client, the IRS, to create a event promotion site using Wordpress/PHP

TaxChanges.us

This project had a very tight turnaround time and we came in on time and in budget using PHP & custom JavaScript

• JohnAbeln.com

Worked with my dad to design and build a website for him to showcase his novels and other writings using PHP and JavaScript

Work experience

The Lacek Group, (http://thelacekgroup.com) Minneapolis, MN January 2019 - present Senior Application Developer

- Application development full life-cycle for client projects in PHP using the Laravel framework
- Worked with project managers to created timelines and budgets

Weber Shandwick, (http://webershandwickminneapolis.com) Minneapolis, MN February 2006 - October 2018 Senior Web Developer

- Managed web development team in full life-cycle development of multiple client projects in PHP, .NET & ColdFusion
- Mentored/trained junior developers in all areas of development
- Used JavaScript/jQuery and other libraries to build interactive and responsive web sites
- Developed web apps/sites integrating 3rd party APIs
- Managed and maintained development of PHP backend for dynamic database driven websites
- Worked with project managers to created timelines and budgets
- Developed and customized web applications including building a custom CMS, a blogging app, discussion board apps in PHP and .NET
- Built custom WordPress themes and worked with existing themes/child themes

- Developed and maintained a starter web app starter kit using Gulp and Webpack as the pre-processor/bundler
- Custom WordPress plugin development for specific client needs
- Animated banner development DoubleClick platform
- HTML responsive email development and distribution

River City Mortgage & Financial, Eagan, MN

August 2002 - February 2006

Web Application Designer and Developer

- Redesigned, maintained and updated several public sites and internal web applications
- Developed and maintained MLS based (broker reciprocity) websites for RHS Realty and Hittnergroup.com using Lasso and MySQL
- Developed and maintained multifunctional intranet web applications Web-based admin tools for intranet administration using HTML, CSS and Javascript
- Developed and maintained online mortgage application
- Wrote/edited and uploaded copy

Tecknowledge Management (<u>knowledgemarketing.com</u>), Minneapolis, MN January 2001 - August 2002 Web Designer/Developer

- Designed graphics and developed layouts for multiple websites
- Managed web development projects through discovery, planning, development and testing
- Updated multiple websites per client requests
- Worked with owners to develop strategy targeting potential clients
- Wrote/edited and uploaded copy